Daniel Yankelovich Papers
© 2002 University of Connecticut
Daniel Yankelovich Papers.
1937-1994
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center
Yankelovich, Daniel.
50.5 linear feet
The Daniel Yankelovich Papers document the career of a noted scholar, social researcher and public opinion analyst from roughly 1955 to 1994.
MSS19950027
Biography
Daniel Yankelovich, noted social researcher and public opinion analyst, was born in 1924 in Boston, Massachusetts. He earned both his bachelor's degree (1946) and M.A.(1950) from Harvard University. Post-graduate studies at the Sorbonne in Paris led Yankelovich to embark upon an academic career. He also holds honorary doctorates from Washington University and George Washington University largely for his work in the public sector.
Yankelovich taught as a Research Professor of Psychology at New York University (1968-1973) and a Professor of Psychology in the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research (1973-1978). In 1981 the University of California at Irvine named him a Distinguished Scholar. In 1996 Yankelovich served as a Senior Fellow at the Harvard University Kennedy School of Government and currently lectures as a Visiting Professor at the University of California at San Diego.
In 1958 Yankelovich temporarily departed academia to found the marketing and research firm Daniel Yankelovich, Inc., which was renamed in 1974 to Yankelovich, Skelly, & White, Inc. He chaired this company from 1958-1986. In 1976, joining former U.S. Secretary of State Cyrus Vance, he founded the Public Agenda Foundation, a nonprofit organization intended "to find and test new ways to present complex public issues." Yankelovich subsequently created the New York Times/Yankelovich Poll in the mid-1970s, which evolved into the New York Times/CBS Poll. He serves as the chairman of DYG, Inc. which he established in 1986. Yankelovich has held directorships at firms such as CBS, Inc., Loral Corporation, Meredith Corporation, Reliance Group Holdings and U.S. West, Inc., among others. He has served as a trustee at the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Education, the Charles F. Kettering Foundation, Brown University, and other institutions and organizations.
Mr. Yankelovich has authored nine books in addition to hundreds of speeches and articles. His books include, Beyond the Beltway: Engaging the Public in U.S. Foreign Policy (1994), Coming to Public Judgment: Making Democracy Work in a Complex World (1991), Starting with the People (1988), New Rules: Searching for Self-fulfillment in a World Turned Upside Down (1981), and Ego and Instinct: The Psychoanalytic View of Human Nature-Revised (1969).
Mr. Yankelovich has a daughter, Nicole, through his first marriage to Hassie Kaboolian. In 1991 he wed Mary Komarnicki, who also worked in the social research/public opinion field after earning a master's degree in Social Ecology from St. Bonaventure University in 1983.
Scope and Content
The Daniel Yankelovich Papers document the career of a noted scholar, social researcher and public opinion analyst from roughly 1955 to 1994. The collection consists primarily of research and draft material for three books, Coming to Public Judgment: Making Democracy Work in a Complex World (1991), Starting with the People (1988), New Rules: Searching for Self-fulfillment in a World Turned Upside Down (1981), and numerous survey projects, such as "The Public, the Soviets, and Nuclear Arms". Although the majority of the public opinion material covers political life, a wide variety social issues receive attention as well. The papers also chronicle Yankelovich's participation in numerous organizations and the involvement of his second wife, Mary Komarnicki Yankelovich, in public opinion analysis.
Organization
Series I: Writings (1947-1992) houses the various writings and related materials of Yankelovich. The series has been broken down into the following subseries: Articles, Books, Other Writings, and Presentations. The Articles subseries contains copies of a number of Yankelovich's many newspaper and journal articles. In some cases there is additional material, such as notes or fan mail. The Books subseries includes varying amounts of r esearch material, drafts, reviews, and miscellaneous material for the three books Coming to Public Judgment: Making Democracy Work in a Complex World (1991), New Rules: Searching for Self-fulfillment in a World Turned Upside Down (1981), and Starting with the People (1988). Interviews for the New Rules book have been restricted until 1/1/ 2009. The material for each book has been typically arranged in order of creation. Documents from the Abrams Lecture Series and the New Framework Group are in this subseries because of their relation to the books. The Other Writings subseries contains copies of odd materials such as reports and book chapters. The Presentations subseries encompasses material associated with the many speeches, discussions, and conference presentations given by Yankelovich. Not all folders contain copies of the presentation text.
Series II: Projects (1949-1994) showcases the materials associated with several major survey projects. The series is broken down into several broad subject categories, such as, Harvard Business Review Projects, Nuclear Policy Projects, Work Projects, and Youth Projects. Each of these subseries embody several projects with the materials for each endeavor arranged in order of creation.
Series III: Organizations/Professional Services (1960-1992) includes any material associated with Yankelovich's professional presence in organizations such as the Carnegie Foundation, the National Science Foundation, Public Agenda Foundation, and firms such as Yankelovich, Skelly, & White, Inc. and WSY Consulting Group. For the most part, the materials include meeting agenda books and reports, but in some cases include a wider range of documents. The series is arranged alphabetically by institution name.
Series IV: Subject Files (1965- 1992) contains source material associated with subjects of interest to Yankelovich, such as education, politics and government, and polls. The documents consist primarily of books, reports, and papers. A collection of Harris Surveys and Business Week/Harris Polls from 1975- 1988 (with some gaps) may prove of particular interest to researchers. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Series V: Related Material (1959-1991) encompasses a wide range of papers not related directly with the material in the other series. For example, there are miscellaneous books and journals, interviews with Yankelovich, two television series proposals, material dealing with Mr. Yankelovich's involvement at New York University, and personal papers. A clippings scrapbook covering the period from 1959-1969 comprises one highlight of this series. The series is arranged alphabetically by general subject headings.
Series VI: Mary Komarnicki Yankelovich (1937-1993) holds the material created by or belonging to Mary Komarnicki. The series is subdivided into Projects and Related Material subseries. The Projects subseries contains additional material pertaining to Coming to Public Judgment: Making Democracy work in a Complex World and the GlobeTrends 1990 project.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of public polling materials. See especially the papers of Elmo Roper, Samuel Lubell, James M. Vicary, and Archibald Crossley. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
In order to maintain the confidentiality of the interviewees, the interviews used for the writing of New Rules: Searching for Self-Fulfillment in a World Turned Upside Down (1981) will be restricted until January 1, 2009.
Acquisition Information
The Daniel Yankelovich Papers were donated to the University of Connecticut by Mr. Yankelovich in October of 1995.
Detailed Description/Box and Folder Listing
- Series I: Writings,undated, 1947-1992
  - Subseries A: Articles,undated, 1956-1991
    - "American Values: Change and Stability," Public Opinion, 1984 Dec/Jan (Box 1:1)
      - Notes (Box 1:2)
    - "The Competitiveness Conundrum," The American Enterprise, 1990 Sep/Oct (Box 1:3)
      - Correspondence, 1990 Jul-Sep (Box 1:4)
    - "A Crisis of Moral Legitimacy," Dissent, 1974 Fall (Box 1:5)
    - "Doomsday Logic and the Draft," Psychology Today, 1982 Mar (Box 1:6)
    - "Tomorrow's Global Businesses," The Futurist, 1991 Jul/Aug (Box 1:7)
    - "Eternal Affairs", 1990 Sep (Box 1:8)
    - Foreign Affairs article: clippings, 1988 (Box 1:9)
    - "German Behavior, American Attitudes," Dimensions, undated (Box 1:10)
    - "Hard Times and Presidential Luck," Psychology Today, 1982 Nov (Box 1:11)
    - "Karl Marx vs. American Business: Round II," BELL Telephone Magazine: reprint, 1969 (Box 1:12)
    - "The Meaning of Hungary", undated
      - Clippings, 1956 (Box 1:13)
      - Draft, handwritten, undated (Box 1:14)
      - Notes, undated (Box 1:15)
    - "New Criteria for Market Segmentation," Harvard Business Review: reprint, 1964 Mar/Apr (Box 1:16)
    - "New Rules in American Life: Searching For Self-fulfillment in a World Turned Upside Down," Psychology Today: fan mail, 1981 Apr (Box 1:17-19)
    - "The Public Mood: Nuclear Weapons and the USSR," Foreign Affairs: reprints, 1984 Fall (Box 1:20)
    - "The Risk Takers," Parade, 1981 May 24 (Box 1:21)
      - Fan mail, 1981 May-Jun (Box 1:22)
    - "Searching for Self- Fulfillment in a World Turned Upside Down," American Demographics, 1982 Mar (Box 1:23)
    - "The Student Revolution Permeates All Our Lives," Detroit Sunday News, 1972 Apr 2 (Box 1:24)
    - "U.S. Voter's Image of an Ideal President", [1960] (Box 1:25)
  - Subseries B: Books,undated, 1947-1991
    - Coming to Public Judgment: Making Democracy Work in a Complex World
      (SEE ALSO: Boxes 95-96)
      - Summaries, undated, 1990 (Box 1:26)
      - Correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 1:27-35)
      - The 1987 Frank W. Abrams Lecture Series, Public Judgment, Syracuse University, 1987 Mar 24-Apr 1
        - Series notes, typescript, 1986 Oct-1987 Jan (Box 1:36)
        - Lecture #1, "The Forces Reshaping American Democracy", 1987 Mar 24
          - Notes and outline, typescript, 1987 Feb 18-20 (Box 1:37)
          - Outline and storyline, 1987 Mar 13-20 (Box 1:38)
          - Notes/draft, handwritten,1987 Mar 18 (Box 1:39)
          - Transcript,1987 Jul 7 (Box 2:40-41)
          - Transcript, Bob Kingston edits,undated (Box 2:42)
          - "Extra material",[1987] (Box 2:43)
        - Lecture #2, "Mass Opinion vs. Public Judgment", 1987 Mar 25
          - Notes, typescript, 1987 Feb 23 (Box 2:44)
          - Notes/draft, handwritten, undated (Box 2:45)
          - Transcript, 1987 Jul 21 (Box 2:46-47)
          - Transcript, Bob Kingston edit, undated (Box 2:48)
          - Audio tape, undated (Box 2:49)
          - Charts, [1987] (Box 2:50)
          - "Extra material", [1987] (Box 2:51)
        - Lecture #3, "Obstacles to Public Judgment on the Nuclear Arms Issue", 1987 Mar 26
          - Notes, typescript, 1987 Feb-Mar (Box 2:52-53)
          - Notes/draft, handwritten, undated (Box 2:54)
          - Transcript, 1987 Jul 27 (Box 2:55-56)
          - Transcript, Bob Kingston edit, undated (Box 2:57)
          - Charts, [1987] (Box 2:58)
          - "Extra material", [1987] (Box 2:59)
        - Lecture #4, "Obstacles to Public Judgment", 1987 Mar 31
          - Notes/draft, handwritten, undated (Box 3:60-61)
          - Transcript, 1987 Jul 28 (Box 3:62-63)
          - Transcript, Bob Kingston edit, undated (Box 3:64)
          - "Extra Material", [1987] (Box 3:65)
        - Lecture #5, "Coming to Public Judgment", 1987 Apr 1
          - Notes/draft, handwritten, undated (Box 3:66)
          - Transcript, 1987 Jul 7 (Box 3:67-68)
          - Transcript, Bob Kingston edit, undated (Box 3:69)
          - Audio tape, [1987] (Box 3:70)
        - Lecture advertisements, 1987 (Box 3:71)
        - List of contacts, 1987 Apr 6 (Box 3:72)
        - Itinerary, undated (Box 3:73)
        - Newspaper clipping, 1987 Mar (Box 3:74)
        - Notes: miscellaneous, undated (Box 3:75)
        - Final proofs (incomplete) and sample book jacket, 1991 Apr (Box 3:76-77)
      - Research material
        - Book summaries and reports
          - Doble, John, Science Policy Priorities and the Public, 1983 (Box 3:78)
          - Durfee Barron, Deborah, and D. Yankelovich, Today's American Woman: How the Public Sees Her, 1980 Dec (Box 3:79)
          - Jaggar, Alison M., Feminist Politics and Human Nature, chapter 3, 1983 (Box 3:80)
          - Kettering Foundation, The Public's Role in the Policy Process: A View From State and Local Policymakers, 1989 Jul (Box 3:81)
          - Mathews, David and Noelle McAfee, An Alternative for Community Development And Education Reform, [1990] (Box 3:82)
          - Peter D. Hart Research Associates, Inc., A Survey of Physicists' Attitudes Toward the Strategic Defense Initiative, 1986 Mar (Box 3:83)
          - Public Agenda Foundation and the Center for Foreign Policy Development at Brown University, U.S. - Soviet Relations in the Year 2010: Americans Look to the Future, 1988 (Box 3:84)
          - Public Agenda Foundation and the Center for Foreign Policy Development at Brown University, The Public, The Soviets, and Nuclear Arms: An Experiment in Public Judgment, 1989 Jun 7 (Box 3:85-86)
          - RAND and The Urban Institute, Program for Research on Immigration Policy, Research Mission and Initial Public Agenda, 1989 (Box 3:87)
        - Book reviews/books to be ordered,undated (Box 3:88)
        - Book/article fragments,undated (Box 3:89)
        - National Issues Forum
          - A Report on the 1985 Forums - pre-publication edition,1986 (Box 3:90)
          - A Report on the 1986-1987 Forums - pre-publication edition,1987 (Box 3:91)
          - On Second Thought: A Report on the 1989-90 National Issues Forums - pre-publication draft,1990 (Box 3:92)
          - DPA Book Summary/miscellaneous ,1986-1988 (Box 4:93-94)
          - The Promise of Democracy - A Source Book for Use with National Issues Forum ,undated (Box 4:95-96)
          - Newsletters,1989 (Box 4:97)
        - Papers and Articles
          - Bell, Daniel, "U.S. Culture, the 1970's: The Spirit of the Age", undated (Box 4:98)
          - Bradford, William, "Predicting the Vote From Pre-Election Polls: Contributions to a Theory of Public Opinion" ,1974 May 24 (Box 4:99)
          - Evans, Sara M., "Women in Twentieth Century America: An Overview", chapter 1 of, American Woman: A Report in Depth ,1987 (Box 4:100)
          - The Harwood Group, "Politics: Initial Observations From Focus Groups",1990 May (Box 4:101)
          - Starr, Frederick, "Soviet Union: A Civil Society",undated (Box 4:102)
          - Yankelovich, D., "How the Public Learns the Public's Business" Kettering Review, 1985 Winter (Box 4:103)
          - Yankelovich, D., "Information, Judgment and Consensus," Kettering Review, 1983 Summer (Box 4:104)
          - Yankelovich D. and John Immerwahr, "A Proposal For a Study of Public Judgment", 1984 Mar 1 (Box 4:105)
          - Yankelovich D. and John Immerwahr, "The Emergence of Expressivism Will Revolutionize the Contract Between Worker and Employer," in Work in the 21st Century, 1984 (Box 4:106)
        - Public Agenda Foundation science project: data, 1989-1990 (Box 5:107)
        - Subject Files
          - Abortion, undated, 1989 (Box 5:108)
          - AIDS
            - Clippings, 1989 (Box 5:109)
            - Notes, 1989 (Box 5:110)
            - Public opinion statistics, 1988-1989 (Box 5:111-115)
            - Public opinion statistics (not used), 1985-1987 (Box 5:116)
          - Arms control: clippings, 1989 (Box 5:117)
          - Arms control agreements and cheating: public opinion statistics, undated, 1984-1988 (Box 5:118)
          - Arms race, undated, 1984-1988 (Box 5:119)
          - Competitiveness data, 1987-1990 (Box 5:120)
          - Competitiveness data - economic, 1987-1989 (Box 5:121)
          - Death penalty, undated, 1986-1988 (Box 5:122)
          - Energy crisis, 1973-1983 (Box 5:123-125)
          - Farms (chapter 13), 1985-1989 (Box 5:126)
          - Flag Burning: clippings, 1989 (Box 5:127)
          - General tactics, dealing with the Soviets - Mushy: public opinion statistics ,1988 (Box 5:128)
          - Greenhouse effect/consciousness raising example
            - Notes, undated (Box 5:129)
            - Public opinion statistics, 1974-1989 (Box 5:130)
            - Clippings, 1989 (Box 5:131)
          - Health care costs: clippings,1989 (Box 6:132)
          - Hostages/terrorism: clippings, 1989 (Box 6:133)
          - Immigration, 1977-1986 (Box 6:134)
          - Live-and-let-live vs. Soviet Union/communism is a major threat to the U.S., 1984-1986 (Box 6:135)
          - Miscellaneous clippings, 1984-1989 (Box 6:136)
          - Miscellaneous public opinion statistics, 1987-1988 (Box 6:137)
          - Misinformation: U.S. policy is not to use nuclear weapons in a conventional attack: public opinion statistics, 1982-1984 (Box 6:138)
          - Mistrust - Societ Union: public opinion statistics, 1989 (Box 6:139)
          - Obstacle: mistrust in U.S.-Soviet relations: public opinion statistics, 1983-1988 (Box 6:140)
          - Oil spills: clippings, 1989 (Box 6:141)
          - Panama Canal, undated, 1976-1978 (Box 6:142)
          - Patriotism, 1974-1986 (Box 6:143)
          - Political candidates and the press, 1981-1987 (Box 6:144)
          - Presidential debates: clippings, 1988 Sep-Oct (Box 6:145)
          - Prayer in public schools, 1986-1988 (Box 6:146)
          - Questions with unclear values component, 1980-1988 (Box 6:147)
          - Savings, 1989 (Box 6:148)
          - Savings and loans: clippings, 1989 (Box 6:149)
          - Strategic Defense Initiative (SDI), 1985-1988 (Box 6:150)
          - Soviet intent: communist expansion vs. peace/protecting our own security, 1988 (Box 6:151)
          - Trade/economics, 1985-1990 (Box 6:152-153)
          - U.S. - Societ relations (chapter 11), 1988 (Box 6:154)
          - Verification - mushy, 1984-1987 (Box 6:155)
      - Chapter D1
        - Definitions, 1952-1964 (Box 6:156)
        - References to methodology, 1947, 1982, 1988 (Box 6:157)
        - "Catchcall", 1987-1989 (Box 6:158)
      - Notes
        - Chapter 7, 1989 (Box 6:159)
        - Chapter 21-23: "consciousness raising," "working through," "obstacle analysis", 1988-1989 (Box 6:160)
        - Miscellaneous, 1988 (Box 6:161)
        - Miscellaneous (in Mary Komarnicki's handwriting), 1989 (Box 6:162)
        - Modernism, 1989 (Box 6:163)
        - Notebook (in Mary Komarnicki's handwriting), [1989] (Box 6:164)
        - Notebook (in Mary Komarnicki's handwriting), [1989] (Box 7:165)
        - Philosophy, 1989 (Box 7:166)
        - V.O. Key: reading notes, 1988 Aug 15 (Box 7:167)
        - "3 stages to public judgment", undated (Box 7:168)
      - Chapter 9 footnotes, 1987 (Box 7:169)
      - Chapter 3 sources, 1975-1978 (Box 7:170)
      - Sources consulted, 1985-1989 (Box 7:171-174)
      - "Discards", 1988-1989 (Box 7:175)
      - Outlines
        - Chapter outlines/summary notes, 1988 Mar-Oct (Box 7:176)
        - Concept map, 1988 Jun 15 (Box 7:177)
        - Master outline: version D, 1988 Jun 20 (Box 7:178)
        - Master outline: version D, 1989 Jul 11 (Box 7:179)
      - Typescript draft introduction,1988 Feb 3 (Box 7:180)
      - Typescript draft B
        - Chapter 1 (B1), "The Qulaity of Public Opinion", 1988 Apr 7 (Box 7:181)
        - Chapter 2 (B2), "Why the Urgency?", 1988 Apr 8 (Box 7:182)
        - Chapter 2 (B2), "Why the Urgency?", 1988 Apr 11 (Box 7:183)
        - Chapter 2 (B2), "Why the Urgency?", 1988 Apr 20 (Box 7:184)
        - Chapter 3 (B3), "A Cultural Misunderstanding", 2988 Apr 26 (Box 7:185)
        - Chapter 4 (B4), "Three Stages to Public Judgment", 1988 Apr 26 (Box 7:186)
      - Typescript draft C
        - Chapter 1, "A Missing Concept", 1988 Sep 6 (Box 7:187)
        - Chapter 1, "A Missing Concept", 1988 Sep 7 (Box 7:188)
        - Chapter 1, "A Missing Concept", 1988 Sep 13 (Box 7:189)
        - Chapter 1, "A Missing Concept", 1988 Sep 16 (Box 7:190)
        - Chapter 1, "A Missing Concept", 1988 Sep 20 (Box 7:191)
        - Introduction - outline, 1989 Jan 31 (Box 7:192)
        - Introduction, 1989 Feb 14 (Box 7:193)
        - Introduction, 1989 Feb 17 (Box 7:194)
        - Chapter C4, "Public Judgment as a Solution", undated (Box 7:195)
      - Chapter C4, "Public Judgment as a Solution", 1988
        - Chapter 4, "Judgment as Knowing", 1988 Oct 14 (Box 7:196)
        - Chapter 4, "Judgment as Knowing", 1988 Nov 28 (Box 7:197)
        - Chapter 4, "Judgment as Knowing", 1988 Dec 7 (Box 7:198)
      - Typescript draft, parts I and II, edited, 1989 Oct
        - Chapter 2, "What is Quality in Public Opinion", 1989 Oct (Box 7:199)
        - Chapter 3, "Mass Opinion vs. Public Judgment", 1989 Oct (Box 7:200)
        - Chapter 4, "DOXA", 1989 Oct (Box 7:201)
        - Chapter 5, "The Bumpy Road From Mass Opinion to Public Judgment", 1989 Oct (Box 7:202)
        - Chapter 6, "Consciousness Raising", 1989 Oct (Box 7:203)
        - Chapter 7, "Transition Obstacles", 1989 Oct (Box 8:204)
        - Chapter 8, "The Expert-Public Gap", 1989 Oct (Box 8:205)
        - Chapter 9, "The Competitiveness Issue", 1989 Oct (Box 8:206)
        - Chapter 10, "From Minutes to Centuries", 1989 Oct (Box 8:207)
        - Chapter 11, "The Cold War: End It or Not?", 1989 Oct (Box 8:208)
        - Chapter 12, "Moving Toward Resolution", 1989 Oct (Box 8:209)
        - Chapter 13, "Ten Rules For Resolution", 1989 Oct (Box 8:210)
      - Typescript draft, parts I and II, 1989 Nov
        - Chapter 1, "A Missing Concept", 1989 Nov (Box 8:211)
        - Chapter 2, "What is Quality in Public Opinion?", 1989 Nov (Box 8:212)
        - Chapter 3, "Mass Opinion vs. Public Judgment", 1989 Nov (Box 8:213)
        - Chapter 4, "DOXA", 1989 Nov (Box 8:214)
        - Chapter 5, "The Bumpy Road From Mass Opinion to Public Judgment", 1989 Nov (Box 8:215)
        - Chapter 6, "Consciousness Raising", 1989 Nov (Box 8:216)
        - Chapter 7, "Transition Obstacles", 1989 Nov (Box 8:217)
        - Chapter 8, "The Expert-Public Gap", 1989 Nov (Box 8:218)
        - Chapter 9, "The Competitiveness Issue", 1989 Nov (Box 8:219)
        - Chapter 10, "From Minutes to Centuries", 1989 Nov (Box 8:220)
        - Chapter 11, "The Cold War: End It or Not?", 1989 Nov (Box 8:221)
        - Chapter 11, "The Cold War: End It or Not?", 1989 Nov (Box 8:222)
        - Chapter 13, "Ten Rules For Resolution", 1989 Nov (Box 8:223)
      - Typescript draft, edited (unidentified editor), 1989 Nov
        - Chapter 5, "The Bumpy Road From Mass Opinion to Public Judgment", Nov 1989 (Box 8:224)
        - Chapter 6, "Consciousness Raising", Nov 1989 (Box 8:225)
        - Chapter 7, "Transition Obstacles", Nov 1989 (Box 8:226)
        - Chapter 8, "The Expert-Public Gap", Nov 1989 (Box 8:227)
        - Chapter 9, "The Competitiveness Issue", Nov 1989 (Box 8:228)
        - Chapter 10, "From Minutes to Centuries", Nov 1989 (Box 8:229)
        - Chapter 11, "The Cold War: End It or Not?", Nov 1989 (Box 8:230)
        - Chapter 12, "Moving Toward Resolution", Nov 1989 (Box 8:231)
        - Chapter 13, "Ten Rules For Resolution", Nov 1989 (Box 8:232)
      - Typescript draft, introduction and part III, edited, 1989-1990
        - Introduction, "The Public is Losing to the Experts", 1989-1990 (Box 8:233)
        - Chapter 14, "Epistemological Anxiety", 1990 Jan (Box 8:234)
        - Chapter 15, "Defining Objectivism", 1990 Jan (Box 8:235)
        - Chapter 16, "Deconstructing Objectivism", 1990 Jan (Box 8:236)